Finding Aid for the Ralph Skene Papers LSC.1215
UCLA Library Special Collections
Ralph Skene papers
1903-1958
1910-1915
UCLA Library Special Collections
Skene, Ralph
LSC.1215
1 unknown (4 boxes)
Ralph Skene was a District Commissioner of the East Africa Protectorate in Kenya's Lamu, Malindi, and Kipini Districts 1897- ). The East Africa Protectorate was later known (after 1920) as the Kenya Colony and Protectorate until Kenya became independent in 1963. The collection consists of Skene's official correspondence and reports while serving as District Commissioner. There is also a diary (1908), notes on the Arab clans of East Africa, photographs and postcards (1903-58).
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift of California Academy of Arts and Sciences.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9929769183606533
Biography
Ralph Skene was a District Commissioner of the East Africa Protectorate in Kenya's Lamu, Malindi, and Kipini Districts. He began working for the East Africa Protectorate in 1897. The East Africa Protectorate, proclaimed by the British on November 19, 1890, was later known (after 1920) as the Kenya Colony and Protectorate until Kenya became independent in 1963.
Scope and Content
Collection consists of official correspondence and reports of Ralph Skene while District Commissioner of the East Africa Protectorate for the Lamu, Malindi, and Kipini Districts in Kenya. Includes a diary (1908) and notes on the Arab clans of East Africa. Also contains photographs and postcards, 1903-58.
Colonial administrators -- Kenya -- Archives.; Skene, Ralph--Archives.
- Lamu, correspondence, 1910-1911. (Box 1, Folder 1-3)
- Miscellaneous, 1910. (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Judicial, registratons of documents, 1911. (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Port and marine, 1911. (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Slavery, 1911. (Box 1, Folder 3)
- History of Poll Tax. (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Probate and administration, 1911. (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Public works, 1911. (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Cash, stamps, estimates, 1911. (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Lamu, correspondence, 1913. (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Lamu, various reports, 1911-1913. (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Kipini, correspondence, 1912-1913. (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Malindi, correspondence and documents, 1912. (Box 2, Folder 1-4)
- Malindi, correspondence and reports, 1913-1914. (Box 2, Folder 5-6)
- Malindi, correspondence and reports, 1913-1915. (Box 3, Folder 1-6)
- Official diary, 1908. (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Notes on the Arab clans of East Africa, compiled by Ralph Skene from the writings of H.C. Hollis, H.R. Tate, J.A.G. Elliot, G.B. Thompson. (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Photographs, including scenes taken in Africa, and postcards addressed to Ralph Skene and others, 1903-1958. (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Photographs, including scenes taken in Africa. (Box 4, Folder 4-5)